I know you, good day, good day,
я вас знаю добрый день добрый
I met you. And where are you from? We're from Ukraine.
я вас встретил А вы откуда Мы из Украины
Good day.
Добрый день А чего светится Россия
I don't know why Russia is shining. We're from Ukraine, and where is such a city from?
не знаю Мы из Украины а откуда такого
what to do Yes, and how are they something,
что Можете это делать Да и как они что-то
they are not so bold now, yes, how they were there for a
они сейчас не такие дерзкие да как были там
couple of months
пару месяцев
[laughter]
[смех]
they are the most stubborn There are
сами упорные Такие попадались
those who said that we bombed for 8 years,
которые говорили что мы бомбили 8 лет
they have even passed a little here,
Они уже даже прошла она немного здесь
Zelensky drug addict and so on,
Зеленский наркоман и так далее
but something now they are short breadwinners
но что-то сейчас они короче хлебальщиков
Do you know any of
знают такие какие-то
these? It’s cool, yes. It’s good
этот так что прикольно да Хорошо хорошо
to catch. If you want to ask something,
ловить чтобы Если хотите что-то спросить
you can ask the children.
можете спросить детям
I’ll make and film this video. I can
сделаю и снимаю это видео документ могу
post the document. If you want, you can, please.
выложить Если хотите О можно пожалуйста
And what channel do you have? I just forgot.
А какой у вас канал можете я просто забыл
Andriy Popyk.
Андрей Попик
We can chat. If you want me to
можем пообщаться Если хотите чтобы я
I called you, I can talk to you if
вас выкли могу что-то поговорить если
you want,
хотите
OK, OK, wait, come on, you know what
Хорошо Хорошо А нет жди давай знаешь чем
I am, what grade are you in,
я вот ты в каком классе
did you pass the 6th grade, did you finish the sixth grade,
это перешел 6 или закончил шестой
yes, look  do you communicate in Ukrainian have
да а вот смотри ты общаешься на украинском
you been in Ukrainian since you were a child did
ты с детства общаешься на украинском или
you communicate a
раньше на русском вас общались
little in Russian before some inserts Yes, I am interested in
немного некоторые вставки Да мне интересно
simply interviewing people who come to
просто опрашивать людей, которые приходят на
Ukrainian, how they transitioned, but come on,
украинский как они переходили а вот Давай
so that I don't torment you with questions, can you
так о чтобы я тебя не мучил вопрос может
convey some greetings or a message to the
передай какое-нибудь поздравление или послание там
audience there to the armed forces  who will watch us
зрителям вооруженным силам кто нас будет
mother and sisters and everyone what is the mother's name
маме и сестры и всем как мама называется
Nadiya and sister Ksyusha Ana come on then
Надежда и сестру Ксюша Ану давай тогда
take a can of Pepsi - if you are a little taller
забери банку пепси-когда чуть-чуть выше
Sit down so that you can be seen So
Сядь, чтобы тебя было видно Да
give mother Nadiya and sister Ksyusha
давай мама Надежда и сестра Ксюша вам
greetings to you from the brother's son and
поздравления и от сына брата и от Андрея
Andrii called  you have a really cool
повика держитесь очень прикольно у вас
guy, he's like that for the sixth grade, but he's
этот парень таков он на шестой класс.
such a lively, cheeky fellow, he likes me,
такой бойкий дерзкий молодец Я ему
you'll grow up to be a proper Cossack,
нравится вырастешь правильным казаком
thank you, let the armed forces
спасибо давай а вооруженные силы пусть лупят
beat the gun so that there are good news for you, of course,
рушню чтобы были хорошие новости тебе конечно
Glory to Ukraine
Слава Украине
[laughter] it's a
[смех]
little funny, well, for me, it's a little
смешно немножко ну для меня немножко
unusual  but let's say that the child has
необычное такое но ну скажем у ребенка
vivid emotions, it's cool, so the boy
живые эмоции это классно так что пацанчик
will watch this, you like it, well done
будешь смотреть этот тебе лайк ты молодец
t  and cheerful positive take and
ты веселый положительный бери и
spread this positive mood
распространяет вот это настроение положительное
to others So why Because now it is very
на других Так почему Потому что сейчас очень
important to raise our population in
важно поднимать нашего населения в
our Ukrainians believe in Ukraine I believe in
нашему украинцам верю в Украину верю в
myself and this is best done through
себя и это лучше всего происходит через
people with Positive because You know with a
людей с позитивом потому что знаете с
sour face like now schedules We have
кислым фейсом как сейчас графиков У нас
everything is under control, there is no
всё Под контролем болегле никакой патики
pain, you can’t do anything, but when you
так тебя не сделаешь ничего, а вот Когда ты в
have a feeling in your heart,
тебя в сердце есть ощущение Вот этого счастья
you can share this happiness and joy with others,
радости ты можешь тогда делиться другими
that’s why
этим зажигать другое назад
we try, maybe try to record some of your
пробуем возможно попробуй свои какие-то там
outbursts, you are
одосеки позаписывать утесы ты
positive, it’s pretty cool, you can
позитивный довольно классно У тебя может
you may not even expect
получится может даже сам не ждать
how much people will start watching you and
насколько люди начнут тебя Смотреть и
even if you watch 10 people, 20
даже если будете смотреть 10 человек 20
there are 100, this is a huge influence, you understand,
там 100 это огромное влияние понимаете
even if your classmates will
даже если твои Одноклассники будут там
watch there and there is also a school there, but you
смотреть и еще там стоит школы it Но ты
will raise interesting topics, fun
будешь поднимать там интересные темы веселые
topics and the right ones  This is how you will
темы и правильные какие-то Так это ты будешь
reach a lot of people,
достучаться до очень многих людей
so everyone looks at us the same way
поэтому все так же кто нас смотрит так
don't really keep it to yourself, most
на самом деле не держите в себе в большинстве
of us have something to say to the world, so if you have something
из нас есть что сказать миру так имеете что
to write, write it on Facebook, there's
писать пишите в фейсбуке там в
Instagram, but not just you know.
Инстаграмма но не просто знаете Я здесь
it is difficult for me to communicate in Ukrainian
общаться на украинском это тяжело мне
at first, but I am
сначала но я
others, someone will read damn it, dude, he has been writing here
других кто-то прочтет блин чувак здесь пишет
for 10 days, there, or 30 days, how does he
уже там 10 дней там или 30 дней как он
switch to Ukrainian, how does he have
переходит на украинский как у него там
difficulties there, and what is easy, what are the
происходит сложности А что легко какие
impressions, and why do I help, that I can’t,
впечатления А чего я помогаю что я не могу
that is, we  we can motivate people
да То есть мы можем мотивировать людей
around us, so we very often
вокруг себя так мы очень часто
underestimate our potential, but I
недооцениваем свой потенциал но есть
love this picture where the
обожаю эту картинку где
matches are standing and one match is lit like that,
спички стоят и одна спичка горит так
and it is symbolic, so I will insert it here
и она символическая вот ее вставлю сюда
later during the installation
затем при монтаже
that one person can light others like this.
что один человек может зажечь других так
That is, you light someone, someone else
То есть вы зажигаете кого-то другого
lights And  here is this
зажигает И вот это е-е
mood, here is what it understands. It spreads like this, that's
настроение вот это понимает Оно распространяется да
why people are shaped by other people, if you
поэтому людей формируют другие люди если вы
see in yourself the power to change the world, and the world
видите в себе силы изменять мир а Мир
changes  actually because of the change in people, so
меняется собственно из-за смены людей да
because the streets become cleaner when people
потому что чисто на улице становится когда люди
realize that first of all, you need to throw less
осознают первое надо меньше бросать
garbage on the
мусор на
street, because someone
улицу Так ведь кто-то все равно будет
will throw endlessly anyway, but you will no longer
бесконечным будет бросать Но ты уже не
throw and you have to clean up,
будешь бросать и надо убирать
organize the appropriate services, and then,
организовывать соответствующие службы и тогда
that is, the garbage itself will not be cleaned  there is an
то есть сам мусор не убирается есть
awareness among people that they need to do less
осознание у людей что нужно меньше
[ __ ] and arrange more around
гадить и больше обустраивать вокруг
themselves, this is the space, then everything becomes, but
себя вот это пространство тогда все становится но
without awareness of this, it will not be like that.
без осознания этого не будет так
For example, in some villages, you can
например в некоторых деревнях можно
observe that there are garbage dumps on the
наблюдать делают мусорники там на
banks of the river on the precipice, so people are
берегу реки на обрыве так есть у людей
just beginning to realize that this is
просто начинает осознание что это
it pollutes the river
загрязняет реку
when there is education here, they don't
когда есть образование здесь не делают
make landfills, they take it somewhere outside the borders,
свалки его выносят где-то за пределы
for example, is it somehow taken to some
например Или как-то увозят на какие-то
other
другие
specialized landfill for
специализированный полигон
household waste, that's why
бытовых отходов назад
I believe I believe that each of us knows this
я верю верю что каждый из нас это такие
as a
знаете как
small agitator of Ukraine in Ukraine,
маленькие агитатор Украины в Украине
even if you can influence two
даже если вы можете влиять на двоих
people  if you have an Instagram page, it
людей если у вас страницу в Инстаграмме
will be there or on Facebook or wherever you
будут там или в фейсбуке или где вы только
are  a Jew reads this, you influence several
людей читает это вы влияете на несколько
people. It often happens that a person
людей Вы бывает часто что человек в чем-то
doubts about something, just switch to
сомневается так же переходить на
Ukrainian, or there, but read
украинский или там или но читай у меня
it, an acquaintance of mine did it, plus, it means it's
знакомый это сделал это плюс значит это
normal, so that is, people very often
нормально да есть люди очень часто
want to compare themselves to some other people,
хотят равняться на каких-то других людей
so get up, get up  leaders of change
поэтому становитесь становитесь проводниками перемен
in Ukraine. We should not wait for
в Украине Мы не должны ждать, что придут
some aliens to come and arrange everything.
инопланетяне какие-то там и все устроят
We should change in our heads. Change
мы должны менять у себя в голове менять
in our
в голове у своего окружения у кого На
heads.  who didn't subscribe? Well, I don't
Подпишитесь Вот кто не подписался Ну я не
know. You are some kind of sinner. You are heartless people.
знаю ли вы какие-то грешные вы бессердечные люди
How can you watch these vidos and not
как можно смотреть эти видосы и не
subscribe. There are a huge number of
подписываться огромное количество
people who watch without a subscription. Well,
людей смотрящих без подписки ну
you have a conscience. Subscribe, it's very
есть Совесть подпишитесь это очень
important. You know why. Because you already come to
важно знаете почему Потому что вы и так
watch vidos, but if there are
Заходите посмотреть видосы но если будет
more  people subscribed to
больше людей подписанных
new unsubscribed people, YouTube
новым не подписанным людям YouTube
will show videos more often, that is, if
чаще будет показывать видео то есть если
there is 1 in the channel  0,000 subscribers see,
в канале там 10 тысяч подписчиков видит
for example, there are additionally 20 unsubscribed
например дополнительно там 20 не подписанных
if 100, then already 200. Well, I simplified it so conditionally,
если 100 то уже 200 Ну я так условно
that's why each of your subscriptions is very
упростил поэтому каждая ваша подписка очень
important. Please subscribe to this
важно пожалуйста подпишитесь на этот
channel, that's
канал это
what I'm asking you.
то что я вас прошу Так именно прошу потому что
comments How much do you believe
оставляйте комментарии Насколько Вы верите в
that each person can change
то что каждый человек может изменить вокруг
a certain number of people around him Glory to Ukraine
себя определенное количество людей Слава Україні
We will win
Мы победим